In this segment, we're gonna look at the
concept of deterministic encryption that
在这一节里，我们来看一下在实际中经常出现的确定性加密的概念
often comes up in practice. When I say
deterministic encryption system, I mean an
当我说到确定性加密系统时，
encryption system that will always map
given message to exactly the same cipher
我的意思是一个加密系统,总是会给消息映射到相同的密文
text. So if we encrypt the same message
three times, every time we'll get exactly
所以如果我们加密相同的消息三次，每次都会得到确切地相同的密文
the same cipher text. So there are no
nonces involved here. Literally this is
这里没有用到随机数
just a consistence encryption scheme that
will always output the same cipher text
从字面上这只是一个一致性加密方案，对于给定的一个特定的消息
given a particular message. So let's see
where this comes up in practice and in
它总是输出相同的密文。那么我们来看看，在实际中，
particular, I want to show you the case of
look-ups into an encrypted database. So
特别是在查询到一个加密的数据库中时。
the settings are imagine we have a server
here that is going to store information
想象我们有一个服务器，信息存储在一个加密的数据库。
inside of an encrypted database. So what
it will store is records, and every record
所以它将存储记录,
has an index and some data that's stored
inside of the record. Now, the first thing
每个记录都有一个索引和一些数据
the server's gonna do is, it's gonna
encrypt this record. So here's a record
服务器要做的第一件事就是要加密这个记录。
became encrypted and you notice that the
index became encrypted with K1 and the
这有一个被加密的记录，你会注意到索引用K1加密，
data is encrypted with K2 and then the
encrypted record is sent over to the
数据用K2加密，这个加密的记录被发送到数据库。
database. And the same thing happens to
many records so that the database overall
许多记录也会被同样处理所以整个数据库会
holds many, many encrypted records. Well,
again, you can imagine that the index is
保存很多很多被加密的记录。再一次，你能想象到
encrypted using the key K1 and then the
data and the records is encrypted using
索引用密钥K1加密，数据用密钥K2加密。
the key K2. Now, if encryption is
deterministic, the nice thing about that
现在，如果加密是确定性的，好处是
is that, at a later time, when the server
wants to retrieve a record from the
在以后，当服务器想从数据库中检索一个记录时，
database, all he needs to do is send to
the database an encryption of the index
他需要做的就是将一个服务器感兴趣的加密索引发送到数据库中。
that the server is interested in. So here,
it would send an encryption of the index,
所以，它将发送一个加密的索引，Alice。
Alice. That again, becomes encrypted, and
the resulting cipher text is identical to
再次被加密，得到的密文
the cipher text that was generated when
the record was first written to the
和当记录第一次被写进数据库时生成的密文是一样的。
database. And the database can then, you
know, find the record that has this
数据库可以发现有加密索引的记录
encrypted index in it, and then send the
result back to the server. The nice thing
然后向服务器发送返回结果。它的好处是
about this is that now the database is
completely in the dark as to what data is
现在数据库完全在黑暗中至于在库中被存储的数据
stored in the database and it doesn't even
know what records are being retrieved by
它甚至不知道被服务器返回的记录是什么
the server since all it sees are basically
requests for encrypted entices. And so
因为它所看到的基本上是被加密的吸引的请求。
this deterministic encryption mechanism.
Let's just do a quick look up in the
所以这是确定性加密机制。我们来做一个快速查找
database given an encrypted index and
we're guaranteed that because of the
在被给定的加密的索引的数据库中，因为确定性加密的性质
deterministic encryption property that the
index is going to be encrypted in exactly
索引将会以完全相同的方式加密,
the same way as if was when the record was
created. And so this should be disturbing
就如当记录被创建时的一样。这应该会令你们中的许多人感到不安
to many of you because we previously said
that deterministic encryption simply
因为我们之前所说的，确定性加密不能被选择纯文本安全。
cannot be chosen plain text secure. The
problem is that an attacker can look at
问题是攻击者可以看到不同的密文
different cipher text and if he sees the
same cipher text twice he knows that the
如果他看到相同的密文两次，他就知道
underlying encrypted messages must also be
the same. So in other words, by looking at
接下来被加密的消息一定也是相同的。所以换句话说，
cipher text, he can learn something about
the corresponding plain text because every
通过看密文，他能学到关于通信明文的一些信息因为
time he sees the same cipher text twice,
he knows that the underlying messages are
每次他看两次相同的密文，他会知道接下来的消息也是相同的
equal. In practice, this leads to
significant attacks, and particularly when
实际上，这会导致很严重的攻击，特别是当消息空间很小的时候。
the message space is small. For example,
if we're transmitting single bytes across
例如，如果我们在网络上传输单一字节,
the network, such as, keystrokes that are
being transmitted one keystroke at a time.
如按键正在传播一个按键。
Then, in fact, an attacker can simply
build a dictionary of all possible cipher
事实上，攻击者可以简单地建立一个所有可能的密码文本的字典。
texts. If it's only single bytes, then
there will only be 256 possible cipher
如果它只是简单的字节，就将只有256个可能的密文
texts. And then, simply by learning what
the decryptions of those cipher texts are,
然后，通过简单地学习这些密码的解密文本是什么,
he can actually figure out all future
cipher texts, simply by looking them up,
他可以找出所有未来的密码文本，通过简单地浏览这些
in this dictionary. And so there are many
cases where the message being so small,
在这字典里。因此,在许多情况下,消息这么小,
where this, deterministic encryption,
simply is insecure. Now concretely, in the
这个,确定性加密,仅仅是不安全的。具体来说，
case of an encrypted database, what the
attacker would see is if there are two
至于一个加密的数据库，攻击者看到的是如果这有两个记录
records that happen to have the same
cipher text in the index position then now
恰好有相同的密文在索引位置中，现在
he knows that those two records correspond
to the same index. So again, even though
他知道那两个记录对应于相同的索引。
he doesn't know what the index is, he
learns something about the corresponding
即使他不知道这个索引是什么，但他能知道些关于通信的纯文本的一些信息。
plain text. I wanted to briefly remind you
that, formally, we say that deterministic
我想简要地提醒你，我们所说的确定性加密
encryption cannot be CPA secure by
describing an adversary that wins the CPA
不是CPA安全的，通过描述一个敌手,赢得了CPA游戏
game. The chosen plain text attack game,
and let me quickly remind you how that
被选的纯文本攻击游戏，让我来快速地给你介绍下它是如何进行的
works. The game starts by the adversary
sending two messages, M zero and M zero.
这个游戏通过敌手发送两条消息开始，M0和M0.
And remember that, in this game, the
adversary is always going to be given the
记住这个，在这个游戏里，敌手总是被给左边消息的加密
encryption of the left message or the
encryption of the right message. In this
或者右边的加密。
case, since he used the same message in
both cases, both on the left and on the
在这种情况下，因为他在两个案例中用了相同的消息，
right, he's simply gonna get the
encryption of the message M zero. In the
他只能得到一个消息M0的加密密文。
next step, he's gonna send the messages M
zero, M1. And now he's either gonna get
下一步，他会发送消息M0和M1.现在他或者得到M0的加密
the encryption of M zero, or the
encryption of M1. And his goal is to tell
或者得到M1的。他的目标就是辨别他得到的是哪个
which one he got. But because the
encryption is deterministic, this is very
但是因为这个加密是确定性的，这对他来说是非常容易做到的。
easy for him to do. All he has to do is
just test whether C is equal to C zero.
他需要做的就是辨别是否C等于C0.
And if C is equal to C zero, then he knows
that he got the encryption of M zero. If C
如果C等于C0，他会知道他得到的是M0的加密。
is not equal to C zero, he knows that he
got the encryption of M1. So he can output
如果C不等于C0，他会知道他得到的是M1的加密。所以他可以输出0.
zero. If C is equal to C0 and output one,
if C is not equal to C0 and his advantage
如果C等于C0，并输出了0，如果C不等于C0，
in this in this particular game would be
one. So it, it would be a high, as high an
在这个特殊的游戏中他会有个优势。
advantage as possible which means that he
attacker completely defeats chosen
所以,这将是一个高,尽可能高的优势,这意味着他攻击者完全击败了被选择的纯文本的安全。
plain text security. Okay so, this is just
a formal way of saying that the attacker
好了，这只是一个正式的方式说,
basically learns more information about
the plain text than he should. So, the
攻击者基本上得到了比他应该知道的更多的纯文本信息。
question is, what do we do? And it turns
out the solution is basically to restrict
问题是，我们该怎么做呢？解决方案基本上是
the type of messages that can be encrypted
under a single key. And so, the idea is to
限制消息的类型，这消息可以被单密钥加密的。
say that suppose the encryptor never ever,
ever encrypts the same message under a
这个想法是说假如加密器从不用单密钥加密相同的消息
single key. In other words the message key
pair is always different and never
换句话说消息密钥对总是不同的，从不重复
repeats. So that for every single
encryption, either the message changes, or
所以对于每一个单独加密，要么消息改变，
the key changes, but, or both change. But
it can't be that we encrypt the same
要么密钥改变，或两个都变。但是我们不能用一个密钥加密相同的消息两次。
message twice under the same key. So why
would this ever happen? Well it turns out
所以这怎么会发生的?
there are very natural cases where this
happens. For example, if the messages
这是在非常自然的情况下发生的。比如，
happen to be random. Say you, the
encryptors encrypting keys and those keys,
如果消息是随机发生，加密机加密密钥和那些密钥,
you know, say are 128 the keys so,
they'll never actually with very high
你知道的，说是128密钥，它们不会有非常高的概率，
probability, they'll never repeat. In this
case when we're encrypting keys, in fact,
它们也从不会重复。在这种情况下当我们加密密钥是，事实上，
is very likely that all the messages that
are encrypted under one master key are
极有可能所有用一个主密钥加密的消息总是不同的，
always distinct because, again, these keys
are very unlikely to ever repeat. The
因为，这些密钥极不可能出现重复。
other reason why messages would never
repeat is simply because of some structure
为什么消息从不重复的另一个原因简单说就是因为在消息空间里的一些结构。
in the message space. For example, if all
we're encrypting are unique user IDs. So
比如，如果我们加密的所有都是唯一的用户IDs。
imagine, in the database example, the
index corresponds to a unique user ID. And
所以想象一下,在数据库示例中,该索引对应一个唯一的用户ID。
if there's exactly one record in the
database for each user, that says that
如果恰好在数据库中有一个为每一位用户的记录，也就是说，
every encrypted record basically contains
an encrypted index, where the index is
每个被加密的记录基本上包含了一个被加密的索引，
distinct for all records in the database.
Okay so these are two reasons why messages
这个索引对于所有在数据库中的记录都是不同的。所以这就是为什么消息可能从不重复的两个原因。
might never repeat. And this is a fairly
reasonable thing that actually does happen
这是一个在实际中经常发生的相当合理的事情。
quite often in practice. So now if the
messages never repeat, now maybe we can
所以现在如果消息从不重复，
actually define security and actually give
constructions to satisfy our definitions.
现在也许我们可以定义安全性,在实际中给出结构来满足我们的定义。
So this motivates the concept of deterministic chosen plain text attacks and
所以引出了确定性选择明文攻击
let me explain what they mean. So as usual
we have a cipher defined as an encryption
我来解释一下。通常我们有一个用加密算法定义的加密机
on a decryption algorithm. So we have a
key space, a message space and a cipher
我们有一个密钥空间、明文空间和密文空间
text space and we're gonna define security
just as normal using two experiments.
我们用两个实验定义安全
Experiment zero and experiment one. And
the game actually looks very similar, it's
实验1和实验2。这个游戏看起来很熟悉
almost an identical game to the standard
chosen playing test attack game where
和标准的选择明文攻击游戏几乎相同
basically the attacker issues queries, so
you can see these queries consist of pairs
攻击者发出询问
of messages, M0 and M1. They, as usual
they have to be the same length and for
询问由M0和M1这对消息组成，通常长度相等
each query the attacker either gets the
encryption of M0 or the encryption of M1
对于每次询问，攻击者得到M0或M1的加密
and the attacker can do this again and
again. He can do this Q times, and at the
攻击者可以重复询问，重复Q次
end of the game he's supposed to say
whether he got the encryptions of the left
游戏最后，他要求说出他得到的是左边消息的加密
messages or the encryptions of the right
messages. So this is the standard chosen
还是右边消息的加密
plain text attack game, but now there's
one extra caveat. Which is to say that, if
这就是标准的选择明文攻击游戏。这里提醒一下
the bit is equal to zero, if B is equal to
zero. In other words, the attacker always
如果这个比特等于0，B等于0
sees the encryption of the left messages,
then it so happens that the left messages
就是说，攻击者总是看到左边消息的加密，左边消息必须都互不相同
must all be distinct. In other words, he
will never get to see the encryption of
也就是说，他永远不会看到两个相同消息的加密
the same message twice, because these left
messages are always distinct. So if the
因为左边消息总是互不相同的
bit B is equal to zero, again, he'll never
see. The same message encrypted under the
因此如果B等于0，那么他永远不会看到相同消息用相同密钥加密
same key. Because, again, these zero
messages, M1 zero to MQ zero, are all
因为这些消息0，从M1,0到MQ，0，都互不相同
distinct. Similarly, we require that all
the one messages are also distinct. And so
同样的，我们要求所有的消息1都互不相同
that, again, if B happens to be equal to
one, the attacker will never see two
那么如果B恰巧等于1，攻击者永远不会看到两个消息用相同密钥加密
messages encrypted under the same key.
Okay? So this requirement that the, all
那么这些要求
these messages are distinct, and
similarly, all these Q messages are
所有这些消息都互不相同，同样，所有这些Q个消息都不同
distinct. Basically captures this use case
that the encryptor will never encrypt the
捕获了这样的用例
same message multiple times using one
particular key. And as a result, the
加密机永不使用一个特定密钥多次加密相同消息
attacker simply can't ask for, the
encryption of the same message multiple
因此，攻击者不能多次请求相同消息的相同密钥的加密
times using the same key. Now, I should
point out as you go back to our, to the
那么回到我们原始的攻击
original attack, here. So, here we go back
to our CPA attack on deterministic
这里我们回到确定性加密的CPA攻击
encryption, you notice that here, in fact,
this is not a deterministic CPA game,
注意，这不是一个确定性CPA游戏
because, here, the attacker did ask for
the same message m0 to be encrypted twice.
因为攻击者不能两次请求相同消息的加密
So, in fact, this attack would be an
illegal attack under the deterministic CPA
事实上，这个攻击在确定性CPA下是不合法的
game. And by ruling out this attack we
actually make it plausible that we might
通过排除这个攻击
be able to give constructions that are
deterministic CPA secure. And so as usual
我们使得对确定性CPA安全下结论更为可信了
we say if the adversary cannot distinguish
experiment zero, when he's given the
通常我们说如果当敌手得到左边消息或右边消息的加密时
encryption of the left messages, from
experiment one, when he's given the
不能区分是实验0还是实验1
encryption of the right messages, then the
scheme is semantically secure. Under a
那么这个机制是语义安全的
deterministic CPA attack. Okay. So as
usual, we ask for what's the probability
在确定性CPA攻击下
that the adversary outputs one in
experiment zero? What's the probability
敌手在实验0中输出1的概率是多少？
that the outputs one in experiment one?
Then if these probabilities are close then
实验1中输出1的概率是多少？如果概率接近的话
his advantage in attacking the scheme is
negligible. And if that's true for all
那么他攻击这个机制的概率是可以忽略的
efficient adversaries then we say that the
scheme is semantically secure under
如果对所有有效敌手都如此，那么这个机制是确定性CPA攻击下的语义安全
deterministic CPA attack. So the first
thing I want to do is show you the cipher
那么首先是我想展示的是
block training with a fixed IV, in fact,
not deterministic CPA secure. And this a
使用固定IV的分组密码不是确定性CPA安全的
common mistake that's used in practice.
There are many products that should be
这是实际中常见的错误
using a cipher that's deterministic CPA
secure, but instead, they just use CBC
许多产品都应该使用确定性CPA安全的密码
with a fixed IV and assume that's a secure
mechanism. And in fact, it's not and I
然而他们只是使用固定IV的CBC，认为这是一个安全的机制，而事实上不是
want to show you why. So suppose we have a
PRP that happens to operate on N bits
我来说明原因。假设我们有一个作用于N比特分组的PRP
blocks. And we're going to use this PRP in
CBC mode. So, you know, if there are five
我们使用这个PRP的CBC模式
blocks in the message then this PRP E will
be called five times to encrypt each one
如果消息有5个分组，那么PRP E会调用5次来加密每个分组
of those blocks. Okay. So here's how the
attack's going to work. Well, the first
接下来的是攻击的方法
thing the adversary is going to do is he's
going to ask for the encryption of the
首先敌手会请求消息0N，1N的加密
message as 0N, 1N. In other words, the
first block is all zeros and the second
就是说，第一个分组全为0，第二个分组全为1
block is all ones. So the left message is
equal to the right message here which
所以左边消息等于右边消息
means that he just wants the encryption of
this 0N, one to the N message. So let's
说明他只想要0N，1N这个消息的加密
see what the cipher text looks like. Well,
for completeness I'm gonna write the IV,
我们来看密文是怎样的。为了完整
the fixed IV, as the first element in the
ciphertext. And if you think about how
我把这个固定IV作为密文的第一个元素
CBC works and the second element in
the ciphertext is gonna be basically the
想想CBC的工作方式
encryption of the IV XOR the first
block of the message. Well in our case the
第二个密文元素将会是IV与消息第一分组的异或后加密
first block of the message is all zeros so
really all we're encrypting is just a
在我们这个例子，消息第一个分组全为0，因此加密的就是固定的IV
fixed IV. So the second block of the
ciphertext is simply gonna be the
因此密文第二个分组就是固定IV的加密
encryption of this fixed IV. So next, what
the adversary's gonna do is, now he's
接下来敌手要做的是
gonna output two messages that are a
single block. So the first message is
输出两个都只有一个分组的消息
gonna be, the message on the left is gonna
be the all zeroes block. And the message
那么第一个消息，左边的消息将会是全0分组
on the right is gonna be all ones block.
So observe that this is a valid query,
右边的消息是全1分组。观察这个有效的询问
because messages on the left are all
distinct. And the messages on the right
因为左边的消息都不同，右边的消息也不同
are also all distinct. So these are all
valid deterministic CPA queries. Now, what
因此这些是有效的确定性CPA询问
does the attacker get in response? Well,
what he'll get in response is the
那么攻击者将会得到什么回应呢？他会得到如下回应
following. If he gets the encryption of
the message on the left. Then, well,
如果他得到左边消息的加密
what's the encryption of the one block
message, zero to the N? It's simply the
即一个分组0n的加密
encryption of the fixed IV, just as we saw
before. However, if he's getting the
正如之前看到的，也就是固定IV的加密
encryption of the message on the right,
well, that's gonna be the encryption of 1 XOR
然而如果他得到右边消息的加密，即1异或固定IV的加密
the fixed IV. That's the definition
of, CBC encryption. So know, you can see
这是CBC加密的定义
basically how the attack is going to
proceed. You notice, if I, here I'll use a
你可以看到攻击是如何进行的。注意，我在这里用不同的颜色
different color here. You notice if these
two blocks happen to be the same, then we
注意如果这两个分组恰巧是相同的
know that he received the encryption of
the message on the left, in other words B
那我们知道他得到的是左边消息的加密，也就是说B等于0
is equal to zero. If they're not the same
then he knows that B is equal to one Okay,
如果不相同，那么他知道B等于1
so he's gonna output zero if, you know, C
of one, which is this block, is equal to
因此他输出0，当C[1]，也就是这个分组，
C1 of one, which is this block, and he's
gonna output one otherwise. So this
等于C[2]，也就是这个分组。其他时候输出1
basically shows that CBC with a fixed IV
is completely insecure. Basically the
所以这证明使用固定IV的CBC是完全不安全的
first block can be very easily attacked.
And, in fact, if the messages are short
第一个分组很容易被攻击
you can again build dictionaries and
completely break systems that kind
事实上，如果消息很短，你可以创建字典
of view CBC with a fixed IV hoping that
it's gonna be a deterministic CPA secure.
然后完全攻陷使用固定IV的CBC的系统
So don't do that. We're actually gonna see
secure deterministic CPA constructions in
所以不要这么做。下一节我们会看到安全的确定性CPA构造
the next segment. So I'll say one more
time, if you need to encrypt the database
所以我再说一遍，如果你需要用一致的方式加密数据库索引
index in a consistent manner, don't use
CBC with a fixed IV to do it. Use the
不要使用固定IV的CBC
schemes that I'm gonna show you in the
next segment. And so let me ask you the
要使用我下节要讲的机制
same question about counter mode with a
fixed IV. Is this gonna be a deterministic
那么对于固定IV的计数器模式，我要问相同的问题
CPA secure system or not? And here, I'm
reminding you what counter mode with a
这是不是确定性CPA安全的系统？我来提醒你什么是固定IV的计数器模式
fixed IV is. Basically, we concatenate the
fixed IV. Fixed IV plus one, Fixed IV plus
我们连接固定IV，固定IV加1，固定IV加L
L. We encrypt all these counters. We
concatenate the results, we encrypt the
我们加密所有计数器，连接所有结果，我们加密所有消息得到密文
message to get the cipher text. So if you
think this is gonna be deterministic CPA
那么你认为这是确定性CPA安全的吗？
secure. So I hope everybody said no,
because basically this is a onetime
我希望每个人都回答不是
padding encryption, and if we use this one
time pad to encrypt distinct messages,
这是一次性密码本，如果我们用一次性密码本加密不同消息
basically we'll be getting a two time pad.
And to see more precisely, here I wrote
那么我们得到两次密码本。为了看得更清楚，我把确定性CPA游戏写在这里
down the, deterministic CPA game. So,
you notice what the attacker will do is he
那么注意，攻击者将会这么做
would start off by asking for the
encryption of the message m. So he would
他首先请求消息m的加密
get here the message m XOR the encryption
of the fixed iv and then he's gonna ask
那么他会得到消息m异或固定IV的加密
for some two distinct messages m0 and m1
that's different from m. So, m, m0 and m1
然后他请求与消息m不同的消息m0和m1
are a three are all three are distinct
messages. And then what he'll get is the
那么m,m0,m1是三个不同的消息
encryption of mb and now he can simply
mount the standard, kinda two time pad
然后他得到mb的加密。现在他可以简单的进行两次密码本攻击
attack. And if this equality here of c XOR c prime is equal to m XOR m zero, he
如果c异或c'等于m异或m0
knows that c prime is the encryption of m
zero. And otherwise he knows it's the
他就知道c'是m0的加密，否则是m1的加密
encryption of M1. So, again, he will
completely win this game with advantage
因此他赢得游戏的优势为1
equals to one. Okay, so again deterministic CPA
with a fixed IV is also
好的，使用固定IV的确定性CPA
completely insecure as a deterministic CPA
cipher. So, don't use any of those
作为确定性CPA密码是完全不安全的
schemes, instead let's use the schemes I'm
going to describe in the next segment.
所以，不要使用这些机制，而要用我下节描述的机制